A Finding Aid to the George Leslie Stout papers, 1855, 1897-1978, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1922-1978; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Box 1-3, OV 8
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1922-1978; 2.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Jefferson, Howard B., 1955; 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Laurie, A. P., circa 1932-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Longstreet, Gilbert W., 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Mahoney, Dennis, 1975-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - McGee, John, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Muilenburg, Walter J., 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Muller, Norman E., 1973-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Newton, Travers, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Nicholson, Virginia and W.E. (Nick), circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Oikawa-Picante, Teri, 1972-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Peabody, Sara and Frank, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Pease, Murray, 1944-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Penasco, Eduardo Nunez J., 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Petersen, Nancy, 1974-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Plenderleith, Harold J., 1940-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Pope, Arthur, 1954; 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Rawlins, F. Ian G., 1940-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Ross, Thorvald S., 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Roth, James, 1971-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Ruhemann, Helmut, 1932-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Includes a black and white photograph of Helmut Ruhemann.
    - Sachs, Paul, 1947-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Sawyer, Charles H., 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Schwartzbaum, Paul M., 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Smith, Frank C. Jr., 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Souers, Philip, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Stinson, Harry and Ruth, 1972-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Swarzenski, Hanns, circa 1973-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Thacher, John S., 1939; 1971-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Tichane, Robin Myron, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Vance, Philip, 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Vigtel, Gudmund, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Ward, Gwen, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Webb, Geoffrey, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - White, Sherman R., 1972-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Professional, 1925-1978; 2.4; Archival Resource Key
    Stout's professional correspondence is with museums, galleries, universities, and other organizations regarding projects or business affairs related to his work as a museum director or art conservation. The Fogg Art Museum folder includes one letter from Agnes Mongan, the museum director, just before her retirement. A few records are in French.
    The materials in this subseries are arranged in alphabetical order.
    The bulk of the materials in this subseries have been digitized, except for duplicates of letters.
    - American Association of Museums, 1975-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
      The American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works was originally called the International Insitute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works - American Group. This folder contains letters with both organization titles.
    - Archives of American Art, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Art Association of Montreal, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Art Dealer & Framer, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Asian Art Museum of San Francisco, 1973-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Balboa Art Conservation Center, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Bay Area Conservation Study and Guild, 1971-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - California Department of Parks and Recreation, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1925-1926; 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1972-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Columbia University Press, 1954-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Cooperstown Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Dover Publications, 1970-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Edmond R. Mansoor Antiquities, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Fogg Art Museum, 1971-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Forest Lawn Memorials - Parks and Mortuaries, 1971-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Foundation of the American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Harvard University, 1926-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Innisfree Foundation, 1960-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Institut Royal du Patrimonie Artistique, 1971-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, 1972-1978; 1954-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - John J. Johnson Collection, 1961-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - John J. Johnson Collection - Oversized Maps of Hillstead in Farmington, Connecticut, 1961-1972; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
    - Library of Congress, 1947-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1958; 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Museos de Arte de Barcelona, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - National Conservation Advisory Council, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - The New Yorker, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Oakland Museum, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Portland Art Museum, 1955-1956; 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - San Francisco Civil Service Commission, 1973-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - San Simeon, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Smith College Museum of Art, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Stanford University, 1972-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - State Department, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Timken Art Gallery, 1971-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Timken Art Gallery, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Timken Art Gallery, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1925; 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Winterthur Museum, 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1947-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1923-1978; 2.5; Archival Resource Key
    Miscellaneous correspondence consists of letters from individuals with three letters or less and unidentified people whose names were illegible or they only signed off with their first names.
    The letters are arranged alphabetically with the unidentified correspondents grouped together in one folder at the end.
    The bulk of the materials in this subseries have been digitized, except for duplicates.
    - A-D, Miscellaneous, 1923-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - F-J, Miscellaneous, 1926; 1954-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - K-M, Miscellaneous, 1943-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - N-R, Miscellaneous, 1931-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - S, Miscellaneous, 1947-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - T-W, Miscellaneous, 1947-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, circa 1944-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Writings, 1927-1978; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3-4
  Writings by Stout include typescript drafts and published articles, speeches, notes, and one folder of images and captions for his book The Care of Pictures. All of the writings are by Stout except for three papers about art conservation that were written by others.
  This series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  3.1: Typescript Drafts, 1927-1978
  3.2: Publications, 1941-1969
  3.3: Notes and Writings By Others, 1948, 1962-1974
  The three papers written by others are grouped together in one folder at the end of the series.
  - Typescript Drafts, 1927-1978; 3.1; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of typescript drafts of essays and articles mostly on the subject of art conservation.
    The typescript drafts are arranged in chronological order.
    - "Andokides", 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Callot's Landscape", 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "Buffalmacco and the Badia Frescoes", 1927-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Giotto's Maxims of Composition", circa 1930-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Art for Your Sake", circa 1930-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Art and Opportunity", circa 1930-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "The State of Knowledge in the Arts", circa 1930-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "An Observation on Italian Painting Method in the Fifteenth Century", 1936-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Worcester Art Museum Graduation Speech, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "The Professional Artist", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "Reattachment of Loose Paint", 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "Windows", 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "Comments on Laminal Disruption", 1955-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Paul Coremans Memorial, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Edward W. Forbes Memorial Service, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "Trial Outline of Conservation in the Arts", 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - "Portland Survey", 1973-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - "Description of Film Cracks", 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Rutherford John Gettens Memorial, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - "Provisional Conspectus of Conservation in the Arts", 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "Changes in Attitude Towards Conservation in the Arts", 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "Early Years of Conservation at the Fogg Art Museum", 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Editorial for Studies in Conservation, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Publications, 1941-1969; 3.2; Archival Resource Key
    Publications contain Stout's articles on art conservation in journals and magazines.
    The materials in this subseries have been arrranged in chronological order.
    - "The Study of Art", 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "The Need for Objective Examination", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "Long-Range Conservation", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - "The Viewpoint of the Conservator", 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - "A Monument of Byzantine Wall Painting - The Method of Construction", 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - "Thirty Years of Conservation in the Arts", 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "A Roman Mosaic Pavement Rebuilt", 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Studies in Conservation, Volume 14, number 4, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Notes, 1948; 1962-1974; 3.3; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries includes images and captions for The Care of Pictures, miscellaneous notes, drafts for the text on holiday cards, and bibliographical notes for a later edition of Stout's book. Also found here are art conservation papers written by others.
    The materials in this subseries have been arranged in chronological order.
    - The Care of Pictures Images and Captions, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1962, 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographical Notes for Dover Edition of The Care of Pictures, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Holiday Card Drafts, circa 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Art Conservation Papers Written by Others, 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Subject Files, 1918; 1943-1978; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 4, OV 8-9
  Subject files concern Stout's work as consultant and his affliations with and memberships in various organizations after his retirement.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  4.1: Consultations, circa 1955-1958, 1971-1978
  4.2: Institutions, 1971-1978
  - Consultations, circa 1955-1958; 1970-1978; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Stout worked as a consultant on conservation projects with museums, universities, and arts organizations. Consultations folders include photographs, reports, floor plans and other miscellaneous materials.
    - Foothill Electronics Museum, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Minneapolis Museum, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Condition Reports, 1972; 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Mosque of Kariye Camii, Istanbul, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mosque of Kariye Camii, Istanbul - Oversized News Clippings, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
    - Mt. Athos, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mt. Athos - Oversized News Clippings, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Museum Condition Reports, 1970-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - San Simeon Floor Plans, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - San Simeon Floor Plans - Oversized, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
    - San Simeon Surveys, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - San Simeon X-Ray Room and Conservation Workroom, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - San Simeon X-Ray Room Ground Plans - Oversized, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
    - San Simeon Historical Monument Inventory and Photographs, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - San Simeon Historical Monument Inventory and Photographs, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - San Simeon Historical Monument Inventory and Photographs, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - San Simeon Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Timken Art Gallery, 1974; 1978; 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Woodside Village Church, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Institutions, 1971-1978; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    Found here are papers documenting Stout's affiliations with art and conservation organizations, councils, and advisory boards. All date after his retirement as the director of the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum in 1970. Documents include meeting minutes, newsletters, photographs, and other assorted materials.
    The bulk of the materials in this series have been digitized except for duplicates.
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - American Association of Museums, 1971-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - American Institute for Conservation Incorporation and By-Laws, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - American Institute for Conservation Newsletters and Minutes, 1974-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Anderson Collection, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Bay Area Art Conservation Guild, 1974-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - College Art Association, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - International Council of Museums, 1972-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - International Institute for Conservation, 1971-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Lone Mountain College, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Mansoor Collection, 1972; 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Mansoor Collection - Oversized News Clipping, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
    - National Conservation Advisory Council, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Radiation Detection Company, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Radiation Detection Company - Oversized Charts about Radioactivity, circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
    - Radiation Safety Certificate, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - San Francisco Bay Area Cooperative, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Western Association of Art Conservators, 1975-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Western Regional Conference, 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section Files, 1918; 1942-1955; 1972-1975; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 5, 10
  This series is comprised of Stout's military records from his service during and immediately after World War II in the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives section of the U.S. Army. The records include certificates, army directives, appointments, forms, reports, four diaries, and a few scattered photographs.
  This series is arranged as four subseries.
  5.1: Military Records, 1918, 1943-1955
  5.2: Monuments Men Publications, 1942-circa 1950, 1972-1975
  5.3: Photographs, circa 1945
  5.4: Diaries, 1944-1946
  - Military Records, 1918; 1943-1955; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    These records include certificates, army directives, appointments, forms, reports, and a few official photographs. There is also a certificate of Stout's honorable discharge from World War I and documentation of his Bronze Star award.
    The records are arranged chronologically to reflect the original order of the documents.
    The bulk of the materials in this subseries have been digitized except for duplicates.
    - Honorable Discharge Certificate, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Original certificate and photocopies.
    - Military Records, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Includes small black and white photographs of George Leslie Stout.
    - Military Records, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Military Records, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bronze Star Medal, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Military Records, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Military Records, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Records on the Exhibition of Paintings from the Kaiser Friedrich Museum, Berlin, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Military Reports, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Military Records, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Military Records, 1951-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Military Records - Undated, 1943-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Monuments Men Publications, 1972-1975; 1942-circa 1950; 5.2; Archival Resource Key
    The printed materials in this subseries largely consist of articles and journals written and signed by several Monuments Men and inscribed to George Stout. Many of the articles are about experiences in the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives (MFAA) Section. There are articles written by Langdon Warner, Lincoln Kirstein, Theodore Sizer, and several others. Some of the papers describe MFAA activities but are not written by Monuments Men. A few records are in French and Japanese.
    The materials in this series are arranged in chronological order.
    The bulk of the materials in this subseries have been digitized.
    - Langdon Warner's Commencement Address, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
      The commencement address is inscribed by Langdon Warner to George Leslie Stout.
    - College Art Journal, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Journal includes articles by Walker Hancock, Marvin C. Ross, and Andrew C. Ritchie about their experiences as Monuments Men.
    - "Some Inside Information Around the 'Forged' Vermeer of Rotterdam", 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - A Walpolean at War, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
      This booklet was written by Theodore Sizer with an inscription to George Stout.
    - La Protection Scientifique des Ouevres d'Art en Temps de Guerre, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
      This booklet was written by Paul Coremans with an inscription to George Leslie Stout.
    - "Arts and Monuments", circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
      This article was written by Lincoln Kirstein.
    - Aperture, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
      This book contains an article written by Lincoln Kirstein and the cover is inscribed by Kirstein to George Stout.
    - Fourth Presentation of the Charles Lang Freer Medal, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
      This booklet was published by the Freer Gallery of Art for the presentation of the Charles Lang Freer Medal to Tanaka Ichimatsu who assisted with art conservation in Japan after World War II. The booklet is inscribed to George Stout by Ichimatsu.
    - Mr. Stinson's 'Pet City' - The Sparing of Kyoto, 1945, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
      Booklet researching the reason Kyoto was spared as a target for the nuclear bomb. The booklet is inscribed by author Otis Cary, a World War II veteran, to George Stout.
  - Photographs, circa 1945; 5.3; Archival Resource Key
    There are 2 folders of photographs about the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives section. One folder contains a few photographs, several of them duplicates, depicting groups of unidentifed soldiers on a ship. Stout is only in two of the images including a group photograph with Lamont Moore, Walker Hancock and other Monuments Men. There are also negatives of 12 images, four of which have been developed into black and white photographs, that show La Gleize Church and the town of Ambleve, Belgium during 1945, probably soon after the Battle of the Bulge.
    - La Gleize Church and Ambleve, Belgium, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Group Photographs of George Stout and Other Soldiers, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)